# **OLIN GROARK**

## WEB DEVELOPER

Full-stack web developer with experience building user-focused responsive websites and developing efficient systems and tools in the private and non-profit sectors. In addition to my firm grasp of Git collaboration, RESTful APIs, and technologies from React and JavaScript to PostgreSQL and Node.js, I have significant experience managing programs, teams, budgets and business development processes for public-facing organizations.

## SKILLS

#### Front End Web Development: React,

JavaScript, JQuery, ES6, CSS3, HTML5, Chart.js, Bootstrap, Materialize

Back End Web Development: Node.js,

PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Python, MongoDB

Technology: RESTful API,

Heroku Cloud Platform, Git Workflow, GitHub

Languages: Advanced Spanish, Beginning Swahili and Japanese

## CONTACT

- cgroark.github.io/groark\_portfolio/
- **♀** Seattle, Washington

in colin-groark/

n cgroark

## **EDUCATION**

#### General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Training 2018

University of Washington, Evans School of Public Policy and Governance MPA: Environmental Policy and Natural Resource Management

Certificate: Environmental Management

Trinity College

BA: International Studies, Hispanic Studies

## RECENT WORK

#### Node.is/Express: Carbon Commuter

Track, log and chart carbon emissions of trips travelled based on distance and mode of transport

- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Google Maps API, Chart.js, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- Data visualizations for distance ratios and carbon emissions using Chart.js JavaScript library
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://carbon-commute.herokuapp.com/

#### React/MongoDB: HouseHub

Create a house profile with roommates. Assign and track chores, house bills, and pantry items, and post memos

- Technologies: React, MongoDB, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://tpcc.herokuapp.com/

#### Node.js/Express: Get Out There

Search for National Parks by state, save your favorite parks, see location and real-time weather forecast

- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML
- RESTful APIs: National Park Service, Google Maps, Weather Underground
- Deployed on Heroku cloud platform: https://get-out-there-parksweather.herokuapp.com/

#### Front end game: Sort It

Race a timer and score points when sorting trash, compostables and recyclables correctly

- Technologies: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS
- Deployed on GitHub pages: https://cgroark.github.io/game-waste/

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### General Assembly

Full-Stack Web Development Student

Seattle, Washington Nov 2017 to Feb 2018

- 12-week immersive full-stack web development training with 480 hours of instruction
- Built responsive user-focused projects drawing on technologies that include React, Express, MongoDB, Node js, PostreSQL, JQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and front-end libraries and frameworks such as Materialize, Bootstrap, CSS Grid and Chart.js.
- Established firm grasp of RESTful API architecture, Heroku cloud platform, Git and GitHub, database structure and modeling, and emerging web development trends
- Worked with cross-functional teams of developers and UX designers to bring week-long and quick turnaround projects to fruition

### Tilth Alliance (Seattle Tilth)

Director, Community Education and Environmental Programs

Seattle, Washington Aug 2015 to Nov 2017

- · Oversaw Tilth Alliance outreach and education programs on resource conservation and stewardship
- Managed 11 person team and \$890K grant and contract portfolio funding seven core programs
- Developed processes to track program deliverables, grant applications and reporting
- Built budget tracking systems in Excel to monitor program expenditures; and SharePoint metrics tracker to monitor
- Led proposal strategy and client interview to secure 5-year \$2.2 million resource conservation contract with Seattle **Public Utilities**

## Envirolssues

Seattle, Washingotn Apr 2013 to Aug 2015

Seattle, Washington

Apr 2012 to Mar 2013

Washington, DC

Business Development Associate

- Managed business development and marketing team for community outreach consulting firm
- Led proposal teams and supported strategy and content to compete for public projects
- Created metrics dashboard and data analysis tools to better assess proposal trends and outcomes

#### **Basel Action Network** Research Intern

• Conducted research and drafted reports on the illegal trafficking of electronic waste

Developed data calculator for app to measure environmental benefits of recycling electronics

#### Management Systems International

Business Development Associate and Consultant

Sep 2009 to Sep 2011, Aug 2007 to Aug 2009

- Coordinated proposal teams to compete for foreign aid projects up to \$21million across seven sectors
- Managed teams to capture technical proposal components within strict deadlines
- · Provided budgetary, recruitment and report-writing support for complex international aid contracts